<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | My site</title>
    <link>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 What happened in my last week?</title>
      <link>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-my-week-went&#34;&gt;How my week went&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was a mix of everything: a bit of studying, a bit of procrastination, and lots of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to be productive, but every time I opened my laptop, I somehow ended up on YouTube or playing a new game.
Still, I managed to get a few things done, so my conscience is (mostly) clear.
Trying to convince myself that rest is also a part of being productive.😪&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Last week</title>
      <link>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week--_-&#34;&gt;My week \ (._.) /&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally managed to finish some long-overdue assignments.
I gave myself a few days off — no tasks, just played video games all day.
Sleep was inconsistent, but I’m trying to pay more attention to it and find some balance.
Overall, last week was really relaxing… so relaxing, it actually stressed me out a little?!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 In last week :D</title>
      <link>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-week-in-two-words&#34;&gt;Last week in two words!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was a battle with code and a constant race against time.
I was working on a program, trying to use a library — turns out, it’s only for x32, and I have a 64-bit system.
Urgent search for an alternative began, with the deadline just 3 days away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical student life: juggling bugs, studying, and trying to get some sleep (plus a bit of gaming to stay sane).
Some days felt like a race against the clock, but what can you do — that’s the reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least coffee exists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 In last week?</title>
      <link>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened-last-week&#34;&gt;What happened last week?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week was extremely intense: early morning classes, urgent homework,
and prepping for exams (why are all the deadlines always on the same day?!).
Despite the workload, I still found time for late-night gaming sessions — I was studying platformer mechanics after all,
that counts as learning too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Unity, I created a prototype of a 2D game and realized two important things:
first, the entire gameplay depends on the precision of jumps and controls, and second, testing is hard but essential.
I’m already working on improvements for the next version!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 What happened in the last week?</title>
      <link>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sayprachanh-lsvnv.github.io:1313/en/post/post1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened-last-week&#34;&gt;What happened last week?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had so much work that needed to be finished and submitted before the deadlines.
It felt like everything piled up at once — assignments, programming tasks, and random urgent matters.
I kept telling myself: &amp;ldquo;Just one more task,&amp;rdquo; but before I knew it, it was already 3 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so focused on getting everything done that I barely slept. Coffee became my best friend,
and sleep — my only salvation. Still, I managed to submit everything on time, and it was a relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to get my sleep back on track and maybe even take better care of myself.
Lesson learned: deadlines matter, but so does sleep!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
